David Calhoun frontend web developer résumé

Full resume available online: https://www.themaingate.net/resume/

Experienced developer with deep understanding of frontend fundamentals and modern frameworks such as React.js. Experience working in environments with unclear requirements, where the greatest challenges often appear before any technical implementation begins.

Email: david.b.calhoun@gmail.com

Website: **themaingate.net**Blog: **davidbcalhoun.com**

Github: github.com/davidcalhoun

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/davidcalhoun

Skills

Frontend: JavaScript (ES6+), HTML5, CSS3, React.js, Webpack and Rollup, Jest, React Testing

Library, Material-UI, Storybook

Backend: Node.js, Postgres, Redis

Job History

> Netflix (Los Gatos, CA) UI Consultant (Nov 2017 to Mar 2019)

> WebMocha (Remote) Web Developer (Remote Contractor) (January 2009 to November 2017)

→ Google (Mountain View, CA) Software Engineer (Aug 2014 to Mar 2016)

Terra Bella (Mountain View, CA) Frontend Web Developer (May 2012 to Aug 2014)

CBS Interactive (San Francisco, CA) Mobile Frontend Web Developer (Contractor) (August 2011 to May

2012)

SMag (Remote) Community News writer (Remote Contractor) (October 2010 to October 2012)

Yahoo! Inc. (Sunnyvale, CA) Frontend Engineer (June 2008 to October 2008, July 2009 to April 2011)

> **Headline Media** Web Developer (Contractor) (April 2008 to June 2008)

Talks and Articles

Bundling JavaScript for Performance: Best Practices (Web Performance Calendar)

A Simple Introduction to Javascript Map and Reduce Array Helper Functions

JSConf talk videos: Philosophy and JavaScript, Realtime Satellite Tracking in the Browser
What Is AMD, CommonJS, and UMD?
Education
Biola University
La Serna High School

References (more available on request)

James Long: Former Frontend Engineer at Skybox (LinkedIn)

Phu Son Nguyen: Frontend Engineer at Yahoo! (**LinkedIn**)